Guide to the Henry Lewis Stimson Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Special Subjects, Series IV
  - Long Island Parkways, 1925 May-1926 June (Box 210, Folder 5-11)
  - Long Island Biological Association
    - Minutes of the Board of Directors Meetings, 1925 December-1929 July (Box 210, Folder 12)
    - Minutes of Executive Committee Meetings, 1926 October-1929 January (Box 210, Folder 13)
    - Committee to Prepare a Model Code for Criminal Procedure, 1925-1927 October (Box 210, Folder 14-15)
  - Nicaragua
    - Memoranda and correspondence of others regarding Nicaragua prior to Henry Lewis Stimson's trip to Nicaragua, May 1927, 1926-1927 (Box 211, Folder 1)
    - Bibliography of material regarding Nicaragua, [1927] (Box 211, Folder 2)
    - Message from State Department to American Legation in Nicaragua explaining Stimson's mission, 1927 April 4 (Box 211, Folder 3)
    - Memo [by Henry Lewis Stimson?] regarding possible compromise over question of retaining Diaz as president, possibly a draft for cable, Henry Lewis Stimson to Kellogg no. 120, May 2, 1927, 1927 May (Box 211, Folder 4)
    - Draft of Henry Lewis Stimson papers on Electoral Supervision as submitted to Diaz et al, duplicated in Diary, [1927 May] (Box 211, Folder 5)
    - Draft of letter on Fiscal Reform and enclosed memo, duplicated in Diary, 1927 May 14 (Box 211, Folder 5)
    - Report on Mission to Nicaragua, Henry Lewis Stimson to Secretary of State and the President, 1927 May (Box 211, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence of others regarding Nicaragua, 1927 June (Box 211, Folder 7)
    - Intelligence Reports of United States Marine Corps, Managua, Nicaragua regarding General Augusto C. Sandino, 1927 July 8-27 (Box 211, Folder 8)
    - State Department Cables regarding Nicaragua, 1927 July-September (Box 211, Folder 9-10)
    - Message of José Maria Moncada to the Nicaraguan People, 1927 September (Box 211, Folder 11)
    - State Department Cables regarding Nicaragua, 1927 October-November (Box 211, Folder 12)
    - Questions to and Answers of José Moncada regarding the upcoming election in Nicaragua, with annotations by Henry Lewis Stimson, 1927 November (Box 211, Folder 13)
    - State Department Cables regarding Nicaragua, 1927 December (Box 211, Folder 14)
    - Memos regarding changes in the Nicaraguan Financial Plan, 1927 (Box 211, Folder 15)
    - State Department Cables regarding Nicaragua, 1928 January 1-27 (Box 211, Folder 16-17)
    - American Electoral Mission in Nicaragua: Executive Memorandum No. 10, 1928 August 2 (Box 211, Folder 18)
    - Summary of Events and Policy from Stimson Agreements to Sep 1, 1928 (Box 211, Folder 18)
    - Summary of Events and Policy from Sep 1, 1928 to Nov 15, 1928, 1928 September 1-November 15 (Box 211, Folder 18)
    - American Electoral Mission in Nicaragua, Report of the Chairman, 1928, First Section (Box 211, Folder 19)
    - American Electoral Mission in Nicaragua, Report of the Chairman, 1928, Second Section, Appendices S and T, and Third Section (Box 212, Folder 1-3)
    - American Electoral Mission in Nicaragua, Report of the Chairman, 1928, Photographic Section (Box 213, Folder 1)
  - Philippines
    - Itinerary of Henry Lewis Stimson visit to Philippine Islands, 1926 August 15-31 (Box 214, Folder 1)
    - "A Survey of the International Situation in the Far East: The Philippine Problem and Proposals for Its Solution," an enclosure in letter from J. Mayhew Wainwright, 1926 November 29 (Box 214, Folder 2)
    - Governor General of Philippines: Itinerary and Notes (Box 214, Folder 3)
    - Diary duplicates regarding Philippines, 1935 February (Box 214, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence of others regarding Philippines, 1926-1961 (Box 214, Folder 5)
  - Edwin Parker Endowment Fund: Organizational Material of the Board of Supervising Trustees, 1931 (Box 214, Folder 6)
  - New York State's Mortgage Companies Crisis, 1934 (Box 214, Folder 7)
  - Clausen Report
    - Report of Investigation by Lieutenant Colonel Henry G. Clausen for the Secretary of War Supplementary to the Proceedings of the Army Pearl Harbor Board, pp.1-37, including Exhibit A (Box 214, Folder 8)
    - Clausen Report, Exhibit B-G, pp. 38-363 (Box 214, Folder 9-15)
    - "Information Made Available to General Short of Threat of War with Japan and of Surprise Attack by Japanese on Pearl Harbor," arranged by Lieutenant Colonel Henry C. Clausen (Box 214, Folder 16)
  - Social File, 1912-1950
    - Social File, 1912-1929 (Box 215, Folder 1)
    - Social File: London Naval Conference, 1930 January-May (Box 215, Folder 2)
    - Woodley Social File, 1930 December-1931 April (Box 215, Folder 3-6)
    - Woodley Social File, May 1931, #1 and #2, 1931 May (Box 215, Folder 7-8)
    - Woodley Social File, 1931 June (Box 215, Folder 9)
    - Social File: Trip to Europe, 1931 summer (Box 215, Folder 10)
    - Woodley Social File, 1931 September-December 14 (Box 215, Folder 11-13)
    - Social File, [1932] (Box 215, Folder 14)
    - Woodley Social File, 1932 January 1 (Box 215, Folder 15)
    - Woodley Social File, 1932 January 19-1933 March (Box 216, Folder 1-4)
    - Social File: Post-1933 (Box 216, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous notes (Box 216, Folder 6-7)
- Family Papers, Series V
  - General Stimson Family Correspondence [Not H. L. S.]
    - Catherine Boudinot Atterbury (Mrs. Lewis Atterbury) and Lewis Atterbury, 1864 Oct, 1868, 1871-73 (Box 217, Folder 1)
    - Mrs. Ossian G. (Lucy Thurber) Howard (Box 217, Folder 2)
    - Dora Wheeler Keith (Box 217, Folder 3)
    - Elizabeth R. Kellogg, undated, 1900-04 (Box 217, Folder 4)
    - Elizabeth R. Kellogg, 1905 (Box 217, Folder 5)
    - Elizabeth R. Kellogg, 1906-1912 (Box 217, Folder 6)
    - Elizabeth R. Kellogg, 1913-14, 1917, 1919 (Box 217, Folder 7)
    - Elizabeth R. Kellogg, 1921-37, 1944 (Box 217, Folder 8)
    - Elizabeth R. Kellogg, 1951, 1955 (Box 217, Folder 9)
    - Elizabeth R. Kellogg, "Reflections on Long Life (Box 217, Folder 10)
    - Candace Catherine 'Stimson, undated, 1901-1907 (Box 217, Folder 11)
    - [C. C. S.] Narration of the Events of the Kaisers Cup Race, [1907] (Box 217, Folder 12)
    - Candace Catherine Stimson, 1908-1914 (Box 217, Folder 13)
    - Candace Catherine Stimson, 1915-19 (Box 217, Folder 14)
    - Candace Catherine Stimson, 1920-21 (Box 217, Folder 15)
    - Candace Catherine Stimson, 1928-32 (Box 217, Folder 16)
    - Candace Catherine Stimson, 1933-44 (Box 217, Folder 17)
    - Candace Catherine Stimson, Scrapbook (Box 217, Folder 18)
    - Candace Wheeler Stimson (Box 217, Folder 19)
    - Frank Stimson, 1871 (Box 217, Folder 20)
    - Frederick Stimson, 1915 (Box 217, Folder 21)
    - Henry A. Stimson, 1859 July - 1865 November (Box 218, Folder 1)
    - Henry A. Stimson, 1866 April - 1868 December (Box 218, Folder 2)
    - Henry A. Stimson, 1870 November - 1876 (Box 218, Folder 3)
    - Henry A. Stimson, 1885-1934 (Box 218, Folder 4)
    - Julia Atterbury arid Henry Clark Stimson, 1860 May - 1864 December (Box 218, Folder 5)
    - Julia Atterbury arid Henry Clark Stimson, 1865 January-March (Box 218, Folder 6)
    - Julia Atterbury arid Henry Clark Stimson, 1865 April - 1873 February (Box 218, Folder 7)
    - John Ward Stimson (Box 218, Folder 8)
    - Lewis A. Stimson, 1861 September - 1864 December (Box 218, Folder 9)
    - Lewis A. Stimson, 1865 February - 1872 April (Box 218, Folder 10)
    - Lewis A. Stimson, 1872 May - 1879 June (Box 218, Folder 11)
    - Lewis A. Stimson, 1888 June - 1905 June (Box 218, Folder 12)
    - Lewis A. Stimson, 1906 January- 1913 (Box 218, Folder 13)
    - Lewis A. Stimson, Diaries, 1864 (Box 218, Folder 14)
    - Lewis A. Stimson, Diaries, 1901-03 (Box 218, Folder 15)
    - Lewis A. Stimson, Diary, 1904 (Box 218, Folder 16)
    - Lewis A. Stimson, Diary, 1905, 1908, 1910 (Box 219, Folder 1)
    - Lewis A. Stimson, Diary, 1914 (Box 219, Folder 2)
    - [Lewis A. Stimson] Speech at Cornell University, Undated (Box 219, Folder 3)
    - Lewis A. Stimson, Copies of letters to various family members, 1864-1865 (Box 219, Folder 4)
    - Lewis A. Stimson, Books (Box 219, Folder 5)
    - Lewis A. Stimson, Scrapbook (Box 219, Folder 6)
    - Mabel White Stimson, 1888-1893 (Box 220, Folder 1)
    - Mabel White Stimson, 1911-1912, [1917], 1921-1922, 1928-1930, 1939-1945 (Box 220, Folder 2)
    - Mabel White Stimson, 1950, 1954-55 (Box 220, Folder 3)
    - Mabel White Stimson, speeches, writing, memorabilia (Box 220, Folder 4)
    - Mary A. Stimson (Box 220, Folder 5)
    - Philip M. Stimson, 1942, 1964-1966 (Box 220, Folder 6)
    - Philip M. Stimson, Notebook and exams from Yale, 1909-10 (Box 220, Folder 7)
    - Quotations from family correspondence extracted by Philip Stimson (Box 220, Folder 8)
    - Lucy Dunham (Mrs. Abner) Thurber (Box 220, Folder 9)
    - Catherine Boudinot Stimson (Mrs., Theodore Weston, 1864-1876 (Box 220, Folder 10)
    - Catherine Boudinot Stimson (Mrs., Theodore Weston, 1928-29 (Box 220, Folder 11)
    - Candace Thurber (Mrs. Thomas) Wheeler, 1846-1850 (Box 220, Folder 12)
    - Candace Thurber (Mrs. Thomas) Wheeler, 1854-57 (Box 220, Folder 13)
    - Candace Thurber Wheeler, 1860 (Box 220, Folder 14)
    - Candace Thurber Wheeler, 1861 (Box 220, Folder 15)
    - Candace Thurber Wheeler, 1862, 1865-1867 (Box 220, Folder 16)
    - Candace Thurber Wheeler, 1868-69, 1871-72, 1874-76 (Box 221, Folder 1)
    - Candace Thurber Wheeler, 1877-1878, 1900, 1918 (Box 221, Folder 2)
    - Candace Thurber Wheeler, poems (Box 221, Folder 3)
    - Candace Thurber Wheeler, book: The Development of Embroidery in America (Box 221, Folder 4)
    - James C. Wheeler (Box 221, Folder 5)
    - Thomas Mason Wheeler, 1848-1850, 1860-1863, 1872 (Box 221, Folder 6)
    - Charles A. White, Frances Eaton White, (Mrs. Charles A.), Lily White, 1882, 1894, 1905-1911, 1921 (Box 221, Folder 7)
    - R.G. Gamble (Box 221, Folder 7)
    - Poems: Unidentified (Box 221, Folder 8)
  - Family Correspondence of Henry Lewis Stimson
    - 1874-1889 Mar (Box 221, Folder 9-21)
    - 1889 Apr - 1891 Mar 15 (Box 222)
    - 1891 Mar 16 - 1892 Oct 31 (Box 223)
    - 1892 Nov 1 - 1908 (Box 224)
    - 1909-1917 (Box 225)
    - 1918 Jan - 1920 Oct (Box 226)
    - 1920 Nov -1929 Feb (Box 227)
    - 1929 Mar - 1938 (Box 228)
    - 1939-1945 (Box 229)
    - 1946 - 1950 Oct, undated (Box 230)
    - Correspondence re: James Wheeler, 1919-1923 (Box 231, Folder 1-8)
    - Correspondence re: Zoe Wheeler, 1921 (Box 231, Folder 9)
  - Family History
    - Stimson Family Genealogy and Family Histories (Box 231, Folder 10)
    - Lewis Atterbury Stimson, M.D., by George A. Boyd (Box 231, Folder 11)
    - Elias Boudinot, Silversmith 1706-1770, by George A. Boyd (Box 232, Folder 1)
    - Elias Boudinot, Patriot and Statesman, Part I, by George A. Boyd (Box 232, Folder 2)
    - Elias Boudinot, Patriot and Statesman, Part II, by George A. Boyd (Box 232, Folder 3)
    - Elias Boudinot, Patriot and Statesman, Part III, by George A. Boyd (Box 232, Folder 4)
  - Personal Memorabilia
    - Memorabilia, 1875-1878 June (Box 232, Folder 5)
    - Phillips Andover, 1881 (Box 232, Folder 6)
    - College Scrapbook - oversize, shelved at end of collection as box 232A, circa 1888 (Box 232, Folder 7)
    - Yale College, 1884-1888 (Box 232, Folder 8)
    - Yale Classmates' Roundrobin Letters, 1894-1898 (Box 232, Folder 9)
    - Class of 1888 (Box 232, Folder 10)
    - Harvard, 1888-1890 (Box 232, Folder 11)
    - Dinner to H. L. S. by members of New York Bar, 1909 May 20 (Box 232, Folder 12)
    - Memorabilia, 1910-1914 (Box 232, Folder 13)
    - College Scrapbook, circa 1888 (Box 232A)
    - Trip to Europe, 1921 (Box 233, Folder 1)
    - Certificate of Appointment, Brigadier General, United States Army Reserve, 1922 May 16 (Box 233, Folder 2)
    - Trip to Europe with American Bar Association, 1924 July (Box 233, Folder 3)
    - Trip to Europe with American Bar Association, 1924 July (Box 233, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence re: health of H. L. S. (Box 233, Folder 5)
    - Memorabilia, 1928-29 (Box 233, Folder 6)
    - Memorabilia, 1931-1938 (Box 233, Folder 7)
    - Memorabilia, 1940-1945 (Box 233, Folder 8)
    - Memorabilia, 1946-1947 (Box 233, Folder 9)
    - Clark Membership Cards, 1947-50 (Box 233, Folder 10)
    - Memorials, Tributes, 1950-1951, 1961 (Box 233, Folder 11)
    - Henry L. Stimson submarine (Box 233, Folder 12)
- Selected Documents of the State Department, Series VI
  - Statements of Matters Pending
    - Statements of Matters Pending, Eastern European Affairs Division -- Protocol Division, 1929 April (Box 234, Folder 1)
    - Statements of Matters Pending -Solicitor's Office -- Western European Division, 1929 April (Box 234, Folder 2)
  - Chiefs of Missions
    - Chiefs of Mission: List of those appointed prior to 1929 Mar 4 and commendatory letters (Box 234, Folder 3)
    - Chiefs of Mission: Appointments, 1929: lists and commendatory letters (Box 234, Folder 4)
    - Chiefs of Mission: Appointments, 1930: lists and commendatory letters (Box 234, Folder 5)
    - Chiefs of Mission: Appointments, 1931: list and commendatory letters (Box 234, Folder 6)
    - Chiefs of Mission: Appointments, 1932-1933: lists and commendatory letters (Box 234, Folder 7)
    - Chiefs of Mission: Separations, 1929-1932, lists (Box 234, Folder 8)
    - Foreign Service Officers: Appointments and Separations, 1929-1933 (Box 234, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous Department Reports
    - Persons appointed under the Department of State since Mar 4, 1929 to the higher positions excepted from Civil Service Rules together with their principal e!ldorsements (Box 234, Folder 10)
    - Treaty Division, Report on Treaty Progress, 1929-1933 (Box 234, Folder 11)
    - Growth of the Department of State and the Foreign Service under the Hoover Administration (Box 234, Folder 12)
    - Accomplishments in Major Policy in American Foreign Relations relating to the Control of the Traffic in Narcotic Drugs, 1929 March 4 - 1933 March 2 (Box 234, Folder 13)
  - History of Legislation
    - Record of Legislation of the 7lst Congress in respect to the Department of State, 1929 April 15 - 1931 March 3 (Box 234, Folder 14)
    - Record of Legislation of the 72nd Congress in respect to the Department of State (Box 235, Folder 1)
  - Memoranda of Conversations
    These memoranda are often, though not always, from the meetings between the secretary and a diplomatic representative. The memoranda are subdivided by country and arranged chronologically within the subdivision.
    - Argentina, Austria, Belgium, Bolivia (Box 235, Folder 2)
    - Brazil, Bulgaria, Canada, Chile (Box 235, Folder 3)
    - China, Colombia, Costa Rica (Box 235, Folder 4)
    - Cuba, Czechoslovakia, Denmark, Dominican Republic, Ecuador, Egypt, Finland (Box 235, Folder 5)
    - France, 1929 April - 1930 December (Box 235, Folder 6)
    - France, 1931 January-October (Box 235, Folder 7)
    - France, 1931 November - 1932 February (Box 235, Folder 8)
    - France, 1932 March - 1933 March (Box 235, Folder 9)
    - Germany, 1929 April - 1931 December (Box 236, Folder 1)
    - Germany, 1932 January - 1933 March (Box 236, Folder 2)
    - Great Britain, 1929 April-September (Box 236, Folder 3)
    - Great Britain, 1929 October - 1931 May (Box 236, Folder 4)
    - Great Britain, 1931 June - 1932 July (Box 236, Folder 5)
    - Great Britain, 1932 September - 1933 February (Box 236, Folder 6)
    - Greece, Guatemala, Haiti, Honduras, Hungary, Ireland (Box 236, Folder 7)
    - Italy, 1929 April - 1930 December (Box 236, Folder 8)
    - Italy, 1931 January - 1932 February (Box 236, Folder 9)
    - Italy, 1932 March - 1933 February (Box 236, Folder 10)
    - Japan, 1929 April-December (Box 236, Folder 11)
    - Japan, 1930 January - 1931 October (Box 237, Folder 1)
    - Japan, 1931 November - 1932 February (Box 237, Folder 2)
    - Japan, 1932 March - 1933 February (Box 237, Folder 3)
    - Lithuania, Mexico, Netherlands, Nicaragua (Box 237, Folder 4)
    - Norway, Panama, Paraguay, Persia, Peru, Philippines (Box 237, Folder 5)
    - Poland, Portugal, Rumania, Salvador, Siam (Box 237, Folder 6)
    - Spain, Sweden, Switzerland, Turkey, Uruguay, Venezuela, Yugoslavia (Box 237, Folder 7)
    - Cabinet, President, Senator Borah (Box 237, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous, 1929 (Box 237, Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous, 1930 (Box 237, Folder 10)
    - Miscellaneous, 1931 (Box 237, Folder 11)
    - Miscellaneous, 1932-1933 (Box 237, Folder 12)
  - Conversations, 1931 July-August
    - Memoranda of conversations: European Trip, 1931 July-August (Box 238, Folder 1)
    - Memoranda of conversations: European Trip (duplicate copies), 1931 July-August (Box 238, Folder 2)
  - Transatlantic Phone Conversations
    - 1931 Jun-Jul (Box 238, Folder 3)
    - 1931 Sep-Oct (Box 238, Folder 4)
    - 1931 Nov (Box 238, Folder 5)
    - 1931 Dec - 1932 Jan (Box 238, Folder 6)
    - 1932 Feb 1-16 (Box 238, Folder 7)
    - 1932 Feb 18 - Apr (Box 238, Folder 8)
    - 1932 May-Jun (Box 238, Folder 9)
    - 1932 Jul-Oct (Box 238, Folder 10)
    - 1932 Nov - 1933 Jan (Box 238, Folder 11)
  - Divisional Reports
    - Briefing Book: Eastern European Division, 1929 March 4 - 1933 January 25 (Box 238, Folder 12)
    - Briefing Book: Far Eastern Division, 1929 March 4 - 1933 March 2 (Box 238, Folder 13)
    - Briefing Book: Far Eastern Division, Appendices #1-10, 1929 March 4 - 1933 March 2 (Box 238, Folder 14)
    - Briefing Book: Far Eastern Division, Appendices #11-43 (Box 238, Folder 15)
    - Briefing Book: Latin American Division, Vol. I (Box 239, Folder 1)
    - Briefing Book: Latin American Division, Vol. II (Box 239, Folder 2)
    - Briefing Book: Latin American Division, Vol. III (Box 239, Folder 3)
    - Briefing Book: Mexican Division (Box 239, Folder 4)
    - Briefing Book: Near Eastern Division (Box 239, Folder 5)
    - Briefing Book: Western Europe Division: Austria, Hungary, Czechoslovakia, Italy, British Dominions (Box 239, Folder 6)
    - Briefing Book: Western Europe Division: France, Germany, Great Britain, Liberia, Netherlands, Scandinavian Countries, Spain, Treaties (Box 239, Folder 7)
    - Briefing Book: Western Europe Division: Disarmament (Box 239, Folder 8)
    - Briefing Book: Western Europe Division: Supervision of traffic in and manufacture of arms, Permanent Court of International Justice, Prevention of liquor smuggling, League of Nations (Box 239, Folder 9)
  - Press Releases
    - 1928 - 1929 Aug (Box 240, Folder 1)
    - 1929 Oct-Dec (Box 240, Folder 2)
    - 1930 Jan-Jun (Box 240, Folder 3)
    - 1930 Aug-Dec (Box 240, Folder 4)
    - 1931 Jan-Jun (Box 240, Folder 5)
    - 1931 Jul-0ct (Box 240, Folder 6)
    - 1931 Nov-Dec (Box 240, Folder 7)
    - 1932 Jan-Apr (Box 240, Folder 8)
    - 1932 May-Sep (Box 240, Folder 9)
    - 1932 Oct-Nov (Box 240, Folder 10)
    - 1932 Dec - 1933 Feb (Box 241, Folder 1)
    - Compilation of releases: London Naval Conference and Treaty (Box 241, Folder 2)
    - Compilation of releases: General Disarmament Conference (Box 241, Folder 3)
    - 1929 Oct 5 - 1930 Dec 27 (bound) (Box 242, Folder 1)
    - 1931 Jan 3 - Dec 26 (bound) (Box 242, Folder 2)
    - 1932 Jan 2 - Dec 31 (bound) (Box 243, Folder 1)
    - 1933 Jan 7 - Feb 18 (Box 243, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous Department of State Publications
    - Memoranda by Division of Current Information, 1932 July 2-8 (Box 243, Folder 3)
    - Lytton Commission Report (1), 1932 September (Box 243, Folder 4)
    - Lytton Commission Report (2), 1932 September (Box 243, Folder 5)
    - Register of the Department of State, 1930 January 1 (Box 243, Folder 6)
    - Register of the Department of State, 1932 January 1 (Box 244, Folder 1)
- Trips to Europe, 1930-1932; Series VII
  - London Naval Conference - accounts, bills, and receipts, 1930 (Box 245, Folder 1)
  - List of American correspondents abroad, 0 (Box 245, Folder 2)
  - Memoranda of press conferences, 1931 July 10-27 (Box 245, Folder 3)
  - Statements for the Press, 1931 July 10 - September 3 (Box 245, Folder 4)
  - Conference of Ministers on Intergovernmental Debts, London, 1931 Jul: preliminary organizational material and proceedings of the first two meetings, 1931 July 20-21 (Box 245, Folder 5)
  - Conference of Ministers on Intergovernmental Debts, London, 1931 Jul: proceedings of third and fourth meetings, 1931 July 22-23 (Box 245, Folder 6)
  - London Conference of Ministers on Intergovernmental Debts: proceedings of the first meeting of the Committee of Finance Ministers, 1931 July 21 (Box 245, Folder 7)
  - London Conference of Ministers on Intergovernmental Debts: proceedings of the second meeting of the Committee of Finance Ministers, 1931 July 22 (Box 245, Folder 8)
  - London Conference of Ministers on Intergovernmental Debts: Resolutions, Declarations, and Press Communiques, 1931 July 21-24 (Box 245, Folder 9)
  - Summaries of the Press, 1931 July 7-14 (Box 245, Folder 10)
  - Summaries of the Press, 1931 July 20-25 (Box 245, Folder 11)
  - Summaries of the Press, mounted clippings, 1931 July 20-24 (Box 245, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous papers relating to Henry L. Stimson's trip to Europe and to the London Conference of Ninisters on Intergovernmental Debts, 1931 July-August (Box 246, Folder 1)
  - Geneva - domestic accounts for stay at Bessinge during Disarmament Conference (1), 1932 (Box 246, Folder 2)
  - Geneva - domestic accounts for stay at Bessinge during Disarmament Conference (1), 1932 (Box 246, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, Speeches, and Writings of Others, Series VIII
  - Correspondence, speeches, and writings of others (Box 247)
  - Correspondence, speeches, and writings of others (Box 248)
- The Office of the Secretary of War Under H.L. Stimson, Series IX
  Scope and Contents
  In 1944 Stimson asked Rudolph Winnacker to undertake a study. of the Office of the Secretary of War during World War II. Winnacker was given access to the Secretary's files as well as to the Stimson diary. In April, 1945, Winnacker began submitting drafts of chapters to Stimson. Work on the study bogged down in May, 1946 with only two of the three projected parts completed. These covered the office through 1943. Little more of the study was ever sent to Stimson, and none of it, so far as can be determined, was published.
  Included in this box are photocopies of the letters of transmittal for the various portions of the study, an explanatory note by Winnacker, an outline table of contents for the completed work, and a listing of the unfinished sections. The drafts for the first two parts of the study, and a chapter in part three on the treatment of Germany follow. Some of the drafts have penciled comments, presumably by Stimson. There are extensive footnotes at the end of each chapter.
  - Part IA -- "The War Department in the National Emergency" (Box 249, Folder 1)
  - Part IB -- "The Strategic Problem" (Box 249, Folder 2)
  - Part IC -- "Defense Aid" (Box 249, Folder 3)
  - Part ID -- "The New Army" (Box 249, Folder 4)
  - Part IE -- "The Problem of Production" (Box 249, Folder 5)
  - Part IIA -- "The Transition from Peace to War" (Box 249, Folder 6)
  - Part lIB -- "The Struggle Against Diversions" (Box 249, Folder 7)
  - Part IIC -- "The Army in Action" (Box 249, Folder 8)
  - Part lID -- "The 8,000,000 Man Army" (Box 249, Folder 9)
  - Part lIE -- "The Home Front" (Box 249, Folder 10)
  - Part IIIB -- "The Treatment of Germany" (Box 249, Folder 11)
- Printed Material, 1884-1949; Series X
  - Printed Material, 1884-1906, 1907-09, 1910, 1911-12 (Box 250)
  - Printed Material, 1913-14, 1914-15 (Box 251)
  - Printed Material, 1916-18, 1919 (Box 252)
  - Printed Material pertaining to the Philippines and Philippine independence, 1915-1934 (Box 253)
  - Reference Material (Box 253)
  - Book: Census of the Philippine Islands: 1918, Vol. I (Box 253)
  - Printed Material, 1921-22, 1923, 1924, 1925 (Box 254)